As before, I'll start off by
和之前一样
writing a function that operates on a single column,
我先写出在单列上运算的函数
which I'll call second_largest_in_column.
我把它称为 second_largest_in_column
Now there are a few different ways that I could find
想要在一列中找出第二大值
the second largest value in a column.
我们有很多种方法
One way that occurs to me is I could sort the column in
一种就是 我把这一列值
descending order,
按降序排列
then look at the second value in the column.
然后找到该列的第二个值
We haven't sorted a panda series before, so
我们还没有对 pandasSeries 进行过排序
I'll start by Googling panda's sort series.
所以 我先用 Google 查一下 pandas sort series
This first link is the pandas documentation page for
第一个链接是 pandas 中
a function called sort.
sort 函数的文档页面
This looks like what I want, but
这个看起来就是我要找的内容
there's a note that this function has been deprecated.
但这里有一个注释称 该函数已被弃用 (deprecated)
And instead, I should use the sort values function with
而我应该使用 sort_values 函数 且 inplace 等于真值
inplace equals true for inplace sorting.
以进行原地排序
I'll click this link at the bottom to see
我单击底部的这个链接
the documentation for the sort values function.
查看 sort_values 函数的文档
I can see that the inplace argument affects whether
我发现 inplace 参数决定
the series will be sorted inplace,
series 是会进行原地 (inplace) 排序
the alternative being to create a new series.
还是创建一个新的 series
Now, I don't want to modify the original series.
我不想更改原来的 series
So I'll use inplace equals false,
因此 我将 inplace 设为假值
which is the default value for inplace.
也就是 inplace 的默认值
I can also see that there's a flag called ascending, which
我还看到 有一个名为升序 (ascending) 的参数
controls whether the series is sorted in ascending or
它控制 series 是按照升序
descending order.
还是降序排列
I'll want to pass false, so
我把它设为假值
that the series will be sorted in descending order.
这样 series 就会按照降序排列了
So here, I'm creating a sorted column by calling
我在这里调用 sort_values 函数并将升序设为假值
the sort_values function with ascending=False.
这样就创建了一个排序后的列
And like I said, I'm using the default value for in place.
我之前说过 我使用了 inplace 的默认值
The sorted column will be a panda's series, so
排序后的列是一个 pandasSeries
I can access the second value using iloc and
我可以用 iloc 来获取第二个值
the second value will be at position one.
第二个值位于位置 1
Now, I'll try calling this function on one of the columns
现在 我要尝试在 DataFrame 的某一列上调用这一函数
in the data frame to see if it works.
以检验它是否有效
It returned 4, which is indeed,
它的返回值为 4
the second largest value in column A.
这确实是 A 列的第二大值
Now I'm ready to take in the second_largest function,
现在 我准备好键入
which will take in an entire data frame.
可传入整个 DataFrame 的 second_largest 函数
The real work has been done already and
具体工作已经完成
now I just need to apply the second_largest_in_column
我现在只需对 DataFrame apply
function, to the data frame.
second_largest_in_column 函数
Finally, I'll call this function on the test data
最后 我要在测试 DataFrame 上调用这个函数
frame and it looks like it worked.
看起来 它能够正常运算